A beginning is
a very delicate time.
Know then, that
it is the year 10191.
The Known Universe is
ruled by the
Padisha Emperor Shaddam IV,
my father.
In this time, the most precious
substance in the Universe
is the spice melange.
The spice extends life.
The spice expands
consciousness.
The spice is vital
to space travel.
The Spacing Guild
and its navigators,
who the spice has
mutated over 4,000 years,
use the orange spice gas,
which gives them
the ability to fold space.
That is,
travel to any part of
the Universe without moving.
Oh, yes.
I forgot to tell you.
The spice exists
on only one planet
in the entire Universe.
A desolate, dry planet
with vast deserts.
Hidden away within the rocks
of these deserts
are a people
known as the Fremen,
who have long held a prophecy,
that a man would come,
a messiah, who would
lead them to true freedom.
The planet is Arrakis.
Also known as Dune.
A secret report
within the Guild.
Four planets have
come to our attention
regarding a plot which could
jeopardize spice production.
Planet Arrakis,
source of the Spice.
Planet Caladan,
home of House Atreides.
Planet Giedi Prime,
home of House Harkonnen.
Planet Kaitain,
home of the Emperor of
the Known Universe.
Send a third-stage
Guild Navigator to Kaitain
to demand details
from the Emperor.
The spice must flow.
Father?
Irulan, you must leave.
A third-stage Guild Navigator
will be here within minutes.
We felt his presence.
I shall want telepathy
during his visit
and a report
when we're finished.
I am your Truthsayer, my lord.
He's here, my lord.
The Bene
Gesserit witch must leave.
Leave us.
Yes, my lord.
We are alone.
We have just
folded space from Ix.
Yes?
How was your journey?
Many machines on Ix.
New machines.
Oh?
Yes.
Better than those on Richese.
You are transparent.
I see many things.
I see plans within plans.
I see two great houses,
House Atreides,
House Harkonnen feuding.
I see you behind it.
Yes.
You must share with us.
The Atreides House is
building a secret army
using a technique
unknown to us.
A technique involving sound.
The Duke is becoming
more popular in the Landsraad.
He could threaten me.
I have ordered House Atreides
to occupy Arrakis
to mine the spice,
thus replacing their enemies,
the Harkonnens.
House Atreides will not refuse
because of the tremendous power
they think they will gain.
Then, at an appointed time,
Baron Harkonnen
will return to Arrakis
and launch a sneak attack
on House Atreides.
I have promised the baron
five legions of
my Sardaukar terror troops.
So the Harkonnens will
rid you of House Atreides.
Yes.
One small point.
Here it comes.
We, ourselves,
foresee a slight problem
within House Atreides.
Paul. Paul Atreides.
You mean, of course, Duke
Leto Atreides, his father?
I mean Paul Atreides.
We want him killed.
I did not say this.
I am not here.
I understand.
Why would they
want the Duke's son killed?
We must have
a look at Paul Atreides.
On Caladan.
The powerful
Bene Gesserit sisterhood,
for 90 generations,
has been manipulating
bloodlines
to produce
the Kwisatz Haderach.
A super being.
On Caladan, Jessica,
a member of the sisterhood
and the bound concubine of
Duke Leto Atreides
had been ordered to
bear only daughters.
Because of her love
for the Duke,
she disobeyed
and gave birth to a son.
Paul. Paul Atreides.
Here we are now. Caladan.
And 1 9 light-years beyond.
Beyond Bene TIeilax.
The training
planet of the Mentats,
the human computers.